<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Abhi&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://siwachabhi.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Abhi&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 16:21:40 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://siwachabhi.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS networking basics</title>
      <link>https://siwachabhi.github.io/posts/aws-networking-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 16:21:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://siwachabhi.github.io/posts/aws-networking-basics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction AWS is great for quickly prottyping infrastructure and flexibility of defining applications. This also introduces some complexity around understanding new concepts related to networking, which developers might not be familiar with. This blog introduces basic AWS networking concepts.
Glossary VPC (Virtual Private Cloud): A virtual network that provides isolation and security for resources within AWS. Think of it as a private data center in the cloud. Subnet: A subset of a VPC that allows you to divide the network into smaller segments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick AWS Infrastructure automations with python boto3</title>
      <link>https://siwachabhi.github.io/posts/quick-aws-infra-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 14:21:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://siwachabhi.github.io/posts/quick-aws-infra-automation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction AWS is excellent to quickly protoype infrastructure proposals. We can access AWS console, manually spin up any service we want, experiment with it and spin it down. When moving to production, we can manage AWS infrastructure as code using CDK and keep it up to date with cloudformation deployments, ensuring software development CI/CD best practices.
Problem There is an apparent gap between these two stages, if infrastructure to be setup is fairly complex and team wants to move very fast to production, to enable faster time to market.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
